wirecard.com 2019-08-14

# Privacy Policy | Wirecard

Last updated on 28.02.2019

### 1\. General

Wirecard AG and its affiliated companies pursuant to Sections 15 et seqq. of the German Stock Corporation Act (Aktiengesetz) ("Wirecard Group") offer their customers products and services involving electronic payment transactions. The objective is to enable companies and consumers worldwide to handle electronic transactions securely and smoothly. Security and the protection of personal data is one of the most important aspects in the context of handling and processing of payments. This is why we place particular emphasis on high data protection standards.

Wirecard AG (“Wirecard”, “we”) operates this website in accordance with the provisions of the European General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 (“GDPR”), the German Federal Data Protection Act (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz, “BDSG”) and all other provisions with relevance in the area of data protection law.  

### 2\. Contact us

The data controller of your personal data is Wirecard AG, Einsteinring 35, 85609 Aschheim, Germany. 

If you have any questions about how we collect, store and use your personal information or would like a copy of the information we hold about you, then please contact our Data Protection Officer. You can either write at the above address or e-mail to: data.privacy[at]wirecard.com.

### 3\. What is this website about? 

On this website, you will find information about our products and services involving electronic payment transactions. The objective is to enable companies and consumers worldwide to handle electronic payments securely and smoothly. Security and protecting personal data are two of the most important aspects of handling and processing payments. So the Wirecard Group has high standards for data protection.

Within this website, we'll provide you with a contact form and information about Wirecard services.  

### 4\. Cookies

Cookies are small text files which are stored locally in your internet browser‘s cache memory, in order to be able to recognise it. Wirecard uses different types of cookies, and we provide further information on these cookies [here](https://www.wirecard.com/privacy-policy/cookies). In general, we use cookies that are necessary for the operation of the website and you cannot opt out of the use of these cookies. In addition, we use cookies that enhance the functionality and use of the website (as further described below in section 5), such as to make use of the website easier for visitors, and in order to be able to design it in a more customized manner. You can choose your individual settings in section 5.4 Information on Web Analysis Tools, or configure your web browser so that it informs you when cookies are stored, or to prevent the storage of cookies. Further information in this context can additionally be found in the help function of your web browser. However, we would like to expressly make you aware of the fact that some parts of this website may possibly no longer function faultlessly without cookies.

### 5\. Processing of personal data and other data by Wirecard during visits of our website

#### 5.1 Information we automatically collect when you access our website

No personal data will be collected, since the IP address is truncated before collection.  

#### 5.2 Information you provide by intentionally contacting us

We offer a contact form on our website. Wirecard will store the personal data provided by you when you send the completed contact form (e.g. name, address, telephone number, e-mail address) in its Customer Relationship Management System („CRM System“). Wirecard will use such personal data

  * to respond to your contact request; 
  * in anonymized form to support our internal business objectives, namely data analyses, revisions, the development of new products, improvement of this internet presence, improvement of our services, detection of usage trends and determination of the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns;
  * in order to prevent and identify abuse or fraud.

The data collected via the contact form will not be forwarded to third parties. Affiliated companies of Wirecard AG pursuant to Sections 15 et seqq. of the German Stock Corporation Act (Aktiengesetz) are not to be regarded as third parties. Wirecard forwards your personal data to affiliated companies where necessary in order to respond to your contact request.

#### 5.3 Information you provide by registering for our newsletter 

On our website, we provide an option to register for our newsletter. 

The information you disclose when registering for our newsletter (such as your email address) is stored in our CRM-System. Wirecard uses this personal data to send you information on a monthly basis which pertains to current topics from the areas of finance, product information, etc.

#### 5.4 Transfer of your personal data 

Your personal data will be used only to the extent necessary to achieve the purposes named in this data privacy statement. Your data will be forwarded to third parties, if at all, only within the limits of statutory regulations. Personal data will be forwarded to government institutions and authorities only within the limits of compulsory national legal provisions, or if those data must be forwarded for legal or criminal prosecution because abusive or fraudulent actions have been committed. Forwarding for any other purpose, especially for address trading, is excluded.

#### 5.5 Information on Web Analysis Tools 

##### 5.5.1 Google Tag Manager 

This Wirecard website uses the Google Tag Manager. Google Tag Manager is a solution enabling marketers to administer Website Tags on an interface. The tool Tag Manager itself (which implements the tags) is a cookie-less domain and does not collect personal data. The tool triggers the below described other tags which themselves may collect data, as described below. Google Tag Manager does not access these data. If a deactivation has been carried out on domain or cookie level, it remains for all tracking tags implemented with the Google Tag Manager. 

##### 5.5.2 Google Analytics

This Wirecard website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service from Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies that are stored on your computer and make it possible to analyse how you utilize the site. The information generated by the cookie (including the IP address) is transferred and stored on a Google server located in the United States. On this website, Google Analytics is extended by the code “gat._anonymizeIp():” to ensure anonymized collection of IP addresses (so-called IP-Masking). This means that Google will truncate/anonymize the IP address for Member States of the European Union as well as for other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address is sent to and shortened by Google servers in the USA.

Google uses the information on our behalf to evaluate how this Wirecard website is used, create reports about the activities on the site for the site operators, and to perform additional services regarding website and internet utilization. Further, Google may pass this data on to third parties, if required by law or if using their services to analyse this data. Google will not associate IP addresses with any other information held by Google. 

You can prevent the storing of cookies by choosing the appropriate settings in your browser; however, we would like to point out that in this case some functionality of the website may not be available to its full extent. Further you can prevent the collection and processing of cookie created data relating to your utilization of the website (including your IP) via Google by downloading and installing the browser-plugin available under this [link](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en "Set Google Analytics opt out cookie"). 

You can refuse the use of Google Analytics by clicking on this  link. An opt-out cookie will be set on the computer, which prevents the future collection of your data when visiting this website.

Further information concerning the terms and conditions of use for Google are available under this [link](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html "Opens internal link in current window"). Further information concerning the data privacy of Google can be found under this [link](https://policies.google.com/?hl=en&gl=uk "Opens internal link in current window").

##### 5.5.3 Google AdWords

We use the so-called Conversion Tracking from Google AdWords. Google AdWords is an online advertising program of Google Inc. If you click on advertising placed by Google, a cookie for the Conversion Tracking is placed on your device. These cookies lose their validity after 30 days and contain no personal data and therefore do not serve identification. If you visit certain websites within the 30-day-validity, Google can recognize that you clicked on the advertisement and that you have been forwarded to our website. Every Google AdWords customer receives a different cookie. The information collected with the aid of the Conversion cookie serves the purpose of creating Conversion statistics for AdWords customers that have decided to use Conversion Tracking. Thereby Google AdWords customers find out the total number of users that have clicked on their advertisement and have been forwarded to their website. However, they do not receive any information that can personally identify a user. 

You can disable the storing of cookies in the settings options at Google (“Google Ad Settings”) using this [link](https://accounts.google.com/ServiceLogin?passive=1209600&osid=1&continue=https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl%3Den&followup=https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated?hl%3Den&hl=en "Opens internal link in current window"). Furthermore, you can make use of the deactivation options available at Network Advertising Initiative under this [link](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/ "Opens internal link in current window").

##### 5.5.4 Google Remarketing

Furthermore, within the Google AdWords services we use the remarketing functions “Google Remarketing for Search” and “Google Display Network Remarketing”. These remarketing reports are used within Google Analytics. Should you wish to opt out of this then please see this [link.](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en "Opens internal link in current window")

“Google Remarketing for Search” and “Google Display Network Remarketing” display relevant ads tailored to you based on the fact that you visited our website by placing a cookie on your machine. The cookie is used to say “This person visited this page, so show them ads relating to that page.” It allows us to tailor our marketing to better suit your needs and only display ads that are relevant to you.

Google Analytics Demographics: We use these reports in Google Analytics, which are pulled from the Google Display Network (3rd party cookies). It includes age, interest groups, gender. We use this data for marketing reporting/intelligence.

##### 5.5.5 Facebook Custom Audience – Use of the Pixel

This Wirecard website uses the pixel function of Facebook Custom Audience. The Facebook Pixel is offered by the social network Facebook. Facebook is registered in Europe as Facebook Ireland Ltd, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland. 

The Facebook Pixel is integrated into this Wirecard website with an "advanced matching" function. The pixel initiates the processing of personal data by Facebook and enables the identification of users via numerous websites. This tracking procedure allows target group-oriented advertising. 

The Facebook Pixel stores a cookie, which is a tiny text file, on your device when you access our Wirecard website. If you are logged in to Facebook at the same time or subsequently log in to Facebook, the visit of this this Wirecard website will be noted in your Facebook profile. That information is stored and processed by Facebook so that a connection to the respective user profile is possible and can be used for market research and advertising purposes. Also, data such as name and e-mail address of non-Facebook users who are not logged on to a Facebook account while visiting this Wirecard website are recorded via the pixel and its "advanced matching" function.  

If you want to prevent the collection of your data through the Facebook Pixel on this Wirecard website, you can use this link.

[](https://www.wirecard.com/privacy-protection/)Facebook processes the data in accordance with [Facebook's Data Usage Policy](https://en-gb.facebook.com/policy.php "Opens internal link in current window").

For more information and details about the Facebook Pixel and how it works, please visit the [Facebook Help Section](https://en-gb.facebook.com/business/help/651294705016616 "Opens internal link in current window"). 

##### 5.5.6 LinkedIn Insight Tag

This Wirecard website uses LinkedIn Conversion Tracking of LinkedIn Ireland, Wilton Plaza, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland ("LinkedIn"). LinkedIn Conversion Tracking is a re-targeting and analysis tool supported by the LinkedIn Insight Tag. The Insight Tag causes a cookie which is a tiny text file to be placed in your web browser when you visit the Wirecard website. The Insight Tag is integrated into this Wirecard website and enables the collection of data such as your IP address or the time of accessing this website or the collection of defined events (such as downloads or page views). In addition, interest-specific and relevant offers and recommendations can be displayed, which depend on the services, information and offers you have accessed on our Wirecard website. Furthermore, LinkedIn can compile statistics with aggregated data about the use and visit of our Wirecard website. If you are a LinkedIn member, demographic information, such as your approximate location, may also be collected. The cookie stored by the Insight Tag in your web browser remains there until it is manually deleted by you or automatically deleted after loading of the Insight Tag for the last time. 

You can generally prevent the storage of cookies in the settings of your web browser. Alternatively, you can specifically object to LinkedIn Conversion Tracking by setting an opt-out cookie that remains on your device until you delete cookies. You can deactivate the LinkedIn cookie using this [link](https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out "Opens internal link in current window"). If you are a LinkedIn member, click on "Opt-out on LinkedIn". Non-members click on "Opt-out".

Further information on data protection at LinkedIn can be found [here](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy#choices-oblig "Opens internal link in current window").

##### 5.5.7 Twitter Pixel

This Wirecard website uses functionalities of Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market St., Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94102, USA. Activities of users can be tracked with the visitor activities pixel after they have seen or clicked on a Twitter advertisement. That way they can capture the effectiveness of Twitter advertisements for the Wirecard website for statistical and market research purposes. The data so collected are anonymous for the Wirecard website, i.e. this Wirecard website collects no personal data of individual users. However, Twitter stores and processes the data about which we inform you according to our knowledge. Twitter can connect this data with your Twitter account and use it for its own advertisement purposes, in accordance with [Twitters privacy policy](https://twitter.com/privacy "Opens internal link in current window"). You can enable Twitter and its partners the placing of advertisements inside and outside of Twitter. Furthermore, a cookie may be placed on your device for these purposes. 

Specific information on conversion tracking and the data protection settings for tailored advertising can be found [here](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20171528 "Opens internal link in current window"). 

By using Twitter and the function “Re-Tweet” the websites visited by you will be connected to your Twitter Account and will be made known to other Twitter users, and data will also be transferred to Twitter. Please note that the Wirecard website does not receive knowledge about the content of the transferred data or their use by Twitter. 

You can change your data protection settings relating to Twitter in your [Twitter account settings](http://twitter.com/account/settings "Opens internal link in current window"). 

##### 5.5.8 Etracker

This Wirecard website uses the services of etracker GmbH, Erste Brunnenstr. 1, 20459 Hamburg ([www.etracker.com](http://www.etracker.com/)) for further web analyses. This service employs cookies which enable a statistical analysis of the use of the Wirecard website through its visitors as well as the display of use-related content and advertisement. 

The so-created data will be processed and stored by etracker on assignment in Germany and are subject to the strict German and European data protection laws and standards. In this regard, etracker has undergone independent audit and certification and has been awarded the data protection quality seal "ePrivacyseal". 

The data processing is carried out on the basis of the statutory provision of Art 6 para 1 lit f GDPR (legitimate interest). Our interest within the sense of GDPR (legitimate interest) is the optimization of our online offering and our web presence. Because the privacy of our visitors is important to us we anonymize or pseudonymize data that may permit a relation to individual persons such as IP address or device ID as soon as possible. A further use, connection with other data of etracker or transfer to third parties will not be done. 

If you want to prevent the collection of your data through etracker on this Wirecard website, visitors can use the following link: [etracker Opt-out](https://www.wirecard.com/#)

### 6\. International data transfer

If necessary under clause 5, Wirecard will transmit your personal data to business partners, service providers and other companies in the Wirecard Group which are located outside the European Economic Area (EEA). However, if we process your personal data outside the EEA, we take suitable measures which guarantee an adequate level of data protection.  

### 7\. Data retention

We store your personal data for as long as it is needed to fulfil the purpose for which they were collected notwithstanding any statutory retention obligations, in particular according to tax or accounting law. 

### 8\. Data safety

In order to protect the personal data against loss, falsification or disclosure to unauthorised third parties, we have taken adequate organisational, technical and administrative measures. Wirecard uses firewalls in order to prevent unauthorised access to servers. The servers are located at a safe location in Germany to which only authorised staff have access. All staff members and all persons involved in the processing of data are subject to an obligation to comply with all laws relating to data protection, and to treat personal data confidentially.

### 9\. Data subjects rights

Under GDPR, visitors as data subjects have certain rights in particular the right to access, correct, update, or request deletion of your personal data that we store about you. 

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, you can do so at any time by contacting us via this [form](https://www.wirecard.com/privacy-policy/form).

You can object to processing of your personal data, ask us to restrict processing of your personal data or request portability of your personal data. Again, you can exercise these rights by contacting us via this [form](https://www.wirecard.com/privacy-policy/form).  

Similarly, if we have collected and processed your personal data with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal data conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal data. For more information, please contact us at the above e-mail address.

Our data protection officer can be reached under data.privacy[at]wirecard.com.
